马其顿  布科沃
BUKOVO MACEDONIA,
南斯拉夫王国
KINGDOM OF SERBS, CROATS AND SLOVENES
你好
Hello.
谢谢，我明天去贝尔格莱德
Thank you. I'll head for Belgrade tomorrow,
但是先说清楚，我不能保证什么
but to be clear, I'm not promising anything.
你去了之后我们很快就到
We're coming right after you.
那么，你为什么需要我？
So, why do you need me?
假装你不知道我们要来
Just act as if you don't know we are coming.
别担心
And don't worry about a thing.
好吧，那我就表现出与世无争的样子
Okay then, I'll behave as if I don't have a care in the world.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我不知道那条项链是从哪儿来的
I don't know where that necklace came from.
我以前从没见过这些信
And I've never seen these letters before.
那是你的私事，别人不需要知道
That's your private matter, no one needs to know.
- 是写信的人杀了她吗? - 有可能
- Did he kill her? - It is possible.
我已经派最好的人去调查了
I have my best people on it. The investigation is in progress.
找到凶手
Find the killer.
我要绞死他
I want him hanged.
升官发财可别忘了我
Remember me when you become a minister.
你这个忘恩负义的混蛋
You ungrateful prick.
巴尔干半岛的阴影 第一季 第三集
BLACK SUN EPISODE 3
他看起来怎么样？
How did he look?
他看起来... 很可疑
Well, he looked... suspicious.
- 真的? - 胶卷不见了
- Really? - The film is gone.
这是我的错，也是我的责任
It's my fault. And my responsibility.
好吧，去睡觉吧
Yeah, okay. Go get some sleep.
我太丢脸了，不知道该怎么办
I'm so humiliated, I don't know what to do.
去睡会儿吧
Go and get some sleep.
明天先去停尸房找巴比奇拿报告
Go to the morgue tomorrow, to Babich,
我们办公室见
and I'll see you in my office.
辛苦你了，坚持住
Thank you. Hang in there.
探长，那个俄国人在牢房里，不是他做的
Inspector, the Russian is in the cell, he didn't move.
我就知道，把这的活干完
I knew it. Finish this.
快点，快点，把尸体抬出去，快点！
C'mon, faster. Take the body out. C'mon!
快点，大家快点！
C'mon people, get a move on!
探长，最近发生了太多事
Inspector, this is too much for me.
我想回家
I'd like to go home.
我也想，但是你不让我回家
I'd like that too, but you won't let me.
你到底在干什么？
What the hell are you doing?
无论你到哪，都会有人头落地
Heads are rolling wherever you show up.
我不知道发生了什么，也不知道为什么
I don't know what's going on or why.
- 但我知道这不是我的错 - 记住这句话
- But I know I'm not to blame. - Remember that sentence.
待会儿录口供的时候再说
You'll need it for your statement.
请这边走
This way, please.
如果我早知道，我就不会等警察来了
If I had known, I wouldn't have waited for the police.
下次你就知道了
Well, you'll know better next time.
实际上应该是第三次
Actually, that'd be the third time.
因为这是第二次
Because this is the second.
你父亲..
Your father...
为他的祖国而死
died an honourable officer.
死得很光荣
For his fatherland.
你应该为他感到骄傲
You should be proud of him.
我们的敌人很残忍
Our enemy is cruel.
我希望有人能为他报仇！
I hope someone will take revenge!
不要为将来担心，从现在开始我会照顾你
Do not worry about the future. I'll take care of you from now on.
我们的一个人被捕了
One of our men is arrested.
我们的一个人被逮捕了，阿廖沙 · 格鲁什尼茨基！
One of our men is arrested. Alyosha Grushnitsky!
他做了什么？
What did he do?
抢劫
A robbery.
就在州检察官妻子被斩首之后
At the house of the state prosecutor.
抢劫了他家
Right after his wife was beheaded.
马上把他弄出监狱
Get him out of jail right away. I want to...
我要亲自审问他
question him personally.
我已经告诉过你了，我不知道那个俄国人是谁
I've already told you, I don't know who that Russian is.
我觉得他不认识内文
I don't think he knew Neven,
我没看到任何人进出，我进去只看到了他的尸体
I didn't see anyone coming in or going out. I just found him.
你为什么要去照相馆？
Why did you visit Sarich?
不然我去哪里找摄影师？
Why anyone goes to a photographer...?
不然我去哪里取照片？
Why anyone goes to get the pictures?
你想要舞会谋杀现场的照片
You wanted a memory from a ball where someone was killed.
我不是为那些照片而来的
I did not come for those photos.
我告诉过你，内文是我的艺术小组的成员
I told you, Neven was a member of my art group and he was supposed
为展览拍照
to take pictures for the exhibition.
是的，但你还有事瞒着我
Yes. But you didn't tell me one thing:
他身上的瘀伤是怎么来的? 你不知道？
how did he get those bruises? That you don't know.
我不知道！
I don't!
但我能猜到
I could guess.
别瞎猜，把一切都告诉我
Don't guess. Tell me everything.
这样对你也有利
It's in your interest.
内文他…
Neven was...
有问题，他是个同性恋
problematic, very complex. He was a gay.
他喜欢男孩，吸鸦片，最近..
He loved boys, smoked opium, and lately...
他开始和一些坏人混在一起
he began to hang out with some very bad people.
- 什么坏人? - 我不知道..
- What bad people? - That I don't know...
我知道他负债累累，很多债主都在找他
I know that he was in debt, and that everybody was after him.
很好，笔录里面写清楚，我要去搜查你的公寓
Good. Write that down while I search your apartment.
等等！
Wait!
你不能这么做，我是目击证人，不是嫌疑犯！
You can't do this. I'm a witness, not a suspect!
谁说你不是嫌疑犯？
Who says you're not?
带她去做笔录！
Take her to write the statement!
你怎么了？
What's wrong with you?
怎么突然这么沮丧？
Why are you so gloomy all of a sudden?
你有什么要告诉我的吗？
Did you get something for me?
什么? 我还什么都不知道
How? We don't know anything.
我们只知道这孩子现在已经三岁了
We know the kid is three years old now.
你的出生证明也没用
And the birth certificate you have is useless.
如果你能记得孩子父亲的名字或地址..
If you could remember the father's name or address...
如果我见到他，我会认出他来的
I'd recognize him if I see him.
- 真的吗? - 当然
- You would? - Sure thing.
他是我的第一个嫖客
He was my first John.
谁是你的皮条客？
And who was your pimp?
那个斯塔夫拉
That Stavra.
也许他知道些什么？
Maybe he knows something?
看看你多聪明... 而且很棒
Look how clever you are... And good.
- 不只是在下面棒 - 是的..
- Not just down there. - Yes...
- 给你，探长 - 上面有什么？
- Here you are, inspector. - What's on them?
- 我的全家福 - 好的
- My family portraits. - All right.
- 做完了告诉我 - 好的，我先下班了
- Let me know when you're done. - All right. My shift is over.
- 如果还有别的事...-没事了，谢谢
- If there's anything else... - No, thanks.
- 日沃因! - 在
- Zhivoyin! - Yes.
把这个还给达维多维奇小姐，她可以走了
Give this to Miss Davidovich. She's free to go.
派两个警官看着她
Have two officers guard her.
达维多维奇小姐，探长很抱歉
Miss Davidovich, the inspector apologises, something came up.
你可以走了
You are free to go.
- 没事了? - 是的
- Free? - Yes.
我们的人会送你回家
Our people will take you home.
米利萨夫
Milisav...
开车送这位女士回家
get the car and take the lady home.
斯维塔，你也一起去
Sveta, go with them.
晚安
Good night.
到了，小姐
Here you go, Miss.
- 你好，同事! - 走开！
- Hello, colleague! - Go away!
你们在等谁? 哪位政客吗？
Whom are you with? Some politicians?
请离开，有人在看着呢
Please, leave. People are watching.
你都不会引人注意
And you are inconspicuous.
听着! 我们在保护这位女士，我们需要知道你是谁
Listen! We're guarding the lady, we need to know who you are.
听我说，混蛋们! 你们有五秒钟时间赶紧滚蛋！
Listen to me, jerks! You have five seconds to fuck off!
明白吗？
Understood?
你没事吧? 我听说了
Are you okay? I heard what happened.
你不用来的，一切都很好
You didn't have to come. Everything's fine.
哪有什么好的
Nothing is okay.
我以为我更聪明
I thought I was smarter.
没人知道发生了什么
Voyin, nobody knows what's going on.
沃因对我不忠
Violet was cheating on me.
你能理解吗？
Can you understand that?
和一个俄国士兵..
With some Russian soldier...
在我的床上... 背着我
In my bed... Behind my back.
还有信件和礼物
There were letters... gifts.
一直以来我觉得自己像个懦夫
All this time I felt like a wimp,
而这…
while here...
我想你现在应该休息了
I think you should rest now.
你明天要参加葬礼
You have a funeral tomorrow.
你要在这过夜吗？
You wanted to sleep here?
我今晚不能一个人
I can't be alone tonight.
你在葬礼的前一天晚上来这里很不合适
It's inappropriate for you to be here the night before the funeral.
对不起
I'm sorry.
整个城市都能看到你在我家门口的保安
The whole city can see your security in front my house.
我明白
I understand.
仔细想想
On second thoughts,
也许我们最近不该见面
maybe we shouldn't see each other for a while.
直到这一切平息
Until all this blows over.
好吧
Alright.
我能把这个留在这儿吗，我现在没法处理
Can I leave this here, I can't deal with it now.
当然
Sure.
谢谢你
Thank you.
卢卡，你在找什么？
Luka, what are you looking for?
请不要生我的气
Don't get mad at me, please.
我会把所有东西都放回去的，别打我
I'll put everything back, just don't hit me.
我来放回去，就好像我每天都打你一样
I'll put everything back. As if I'm hitting you every day.
你能帮帮我吗? 我得去上学
Can you help me, please. I have to go to school,
我找不到我的课本了
and I can't find my reader.
卢卡，星期天不用上学
Luka, there's no school on Sundays.
-哦，星期天... 不用上学 -来吧，把这些书收起来,
- Oh, Sunday. Yes... No school. - C'mon, put these books away,
-然后我们一起吃早餐，好吗? -那我吃完饭可以出去玩吗？
- and we'll have breakfast. Okay? - Can I go out to play later?
- 如果你学会押韵的话 -什么押韵？
- If you learn your rhymes. - What rhymes?
- 茨维塔，拜托... -这能帮助他恢复记忆
- Tzveta, please... - It helps his memory.
我让你照顾他并且一直陪在他身边
I asked you to take care of him and to be with him all the time,
不是为了让你陪他做这些疯狂的事
not to encourage his madness.
那我该怎么跟他说？
And what am I supposed to tell him?
像你这样告诉他真相? 他会害怕的
Hit him with the truth as you do? He'd get scared.
照顾一个健康的孩子总比照顾一个疯狂的老人要好
It's better to take care of a healthy child than a crazy old man.
好吧，总之一直陪着他
Fine, just be with him at all times.
别担心
Don't worry.
给你
Here.
如果牛奶可以在河里轻松流淌
If milk could run in a river with ease,
每个人都会... 吃奶酪
Everyone would... nib the cheese.
如果我们能有一个无尽的五月,
If we could have an endless May,
寒冷将不得不远离
Cold would have to stay away.
如果多瑙河是热的,
If the Danube was hot,
每个人都会吃鱼汤
Everyone would eat fish broth.
如果..
If...
但这不可能..
but it can't be...
所以不要谈论你看不见的东西
So don't speak of things... that you can't see.
发射，雷科！
Now, Rayko!
狗娘养的！
Motherfucker!
将军，您能抽出时间跟我见面
General, it is my great honour that you have found time
是我的荣幸
for this conversation.
请允许我自我介绍一下
Please allow me to introduce myself. Alimpiye Mirich.
你喜欢打猎吗，先生？
Do you like hunting, sir?
我鄙视任何暴力行为，即使是对动物
I despise any act of violence, even to the animals.
如果我没理解错的话,
If I understood correctly,
你想要一个有垄断特权的国有公司
you want a privileged state company that would have a monopoly
购买，出口和加工马其顿罂粟？
on the purchase, export and processing of Macedonian poppy?
伟大的马克 · 安东尼曾经说过:
The great Mark Antony once said:
“亲近你的朋友，更要亲近你的敌人”
“Keep your friends close but your enemies closer.”
马克？
Mark?
你想要什么，米里奇？
What do you want, Mirich?
通过建立这个国有公司
By establishing this state company,
我们可以阻止鸦片的非法交易
we would prevent illegal trade in opiates.
切断马其顿恐怖分子的经济来源
Which, I suppose, finances Macedonian terrorists.
我们会从南方的农民那里购买所有的罂粟
We would buy all poppy from the peasants in the south,
为世界提供最高质量的产品
and supply the world with top quality
药用鸦片和吗啡
medical opium; Morphine.
更不用说鸦片出口的税收了
Not to mention the tax receipts from opium exports.
还有你的口袋？
And your pockets, too. Huh?
将军，不只是我的
Not only mine, general. Not only mine.
那些在塞尔维亚南部制造混乱的混蛋..
Those bastards that are wreaking havoc in southern Serbia...
他们最近加入了克罗地亚分裂分子的行列
They've recently joined the ranks with Croatian separatists.
这是一个很严重的问题
It's a terrible problem.
而你却想通过卖药来解决，是吗？
And you'd like to solve it with pharmacy, huh?
我亲爱的米里奇
My dear Mirich...
部长先生坚决支持我的想法
Mr. Minister firmly supports my idea.
我还真是一丁点都不在乎呢
You can't even imagine how much I don't give a flying fuck...
将军，有什么办法可以说服你吗？
General, is there a way I could convince you otherwise?
现在不行，以后也不行，永远都不行
Not now, not ever.
永远不要说永远，将军
Well, never say never, Mr. General, Sir.
这句也是某个智者告诉你的？
A wise man told you that too?
祝你今天过得愉快
Have a nice day.
- 你好 -寄信还是电报？
- Hello. - A letter or a telegram?
我想要寄一份电报
I'd like a telegram. Unless you have some cookies.
我听着呢
I'm listening.
“客户突然来到贝尔格莱德
“The customer has unexpectedly come to Belgrade.
我会给他量尺寸的”
I'll try to take his measurements.”
这就是你要传达的信息？
That's the message?
- 是的 -地址？
- Yes. - Address?
这个月我们不得不再次降低军校学员的工资
We had to reduce cadets' salaries again this month.
快要撑不住了
Things are falling apart.
人们被迫寻找其他收入来源
People are being forced to find other sources of income.
我们正在尽全力
We are doing everything we can.
很抱歉我们没能找到一个体面的方法
I'm sorry we were unable to find an honourable way.
我也很抱歉
I'm sorry, too.
我很抱歉..
I'm sorry that...
我帮不上什么忙
I couldn't be of more help.
但是我觉得我们的麻烦很快就会结束
But I feel that our troubles will soon be over.
我们将在春天发动进攻
We'll launch an offensive in the spring.
怎么? 你不再相信我了？
What? You don't trust me anymore?
我已经信任你十年了，将军
I've trusted you for ten years, general.
如果有必要的话，我可以再相信你一百一千次！
And I will trust you a hundred and ten more if necessary!
我希望上帝仍与我们同在
I hope that God is still with us.
把从我这里偷走的东西找回来
Bring back what was stolen from me.
我们正在尽全力，将军
We're doing everything we can, general.
那被捕的格鲁什尼茨基呢？
What about the arrested Grushnitsky?
我们警方的人正在处理
Our people in the police are dealing with it.
你必须去医院！
You have to go to the hospital!
伤口已经感染了
You're this close to sepsis.
我要给你的伤口消毒，否则...这条腿就保不住了
I need to sterilise your wound, or... You'll lose your leg. Yes.
不，不...不能没有腿！
No, no... Not the leg!
- 愿上帝保佑，塔尼 -他最好..
- May God help Tane. - He better...
- 在你给我的私酿烈酒之后保佑我 -别这样
- after that moonshine you gave me. - Don't be like that.
我的白兰地像眼泪一样纯净
My brandy is clean as a tear.
是你喝太多了
It was you who went too far.
我总是喝太多
I always go too far.
有一个家伙饮酒过量，再也没醒过来
There was a guy who went too far and never came back.
- 早安-早安
- Good morning. - Good morning.
这些西红柿跟我昨天买的一样吗？
Are those the same tomatoes I took yesterday?
是的，如果你付钱的话
Yes, if you pay.
我付钱有点晚，但我一定会付
I always pay. A bit late, but I pay.
- 早上好，老头 -早上好，有什么可以帮你的吗？
- Good morning, old man. - Good morning. How can I help you?
- 你这卖奶油吗? -别的都可以没有
- Do you have Kaymak? - I can run out of everything,
- 但是奶油永不断货 -是塞尔维亚的吗？
- but that I always have! - Is it Serbian?
- 所有这些都是 - 这可不好说
- Everything is. - Well, that's up for discussion.
来尝尝
Here, taste.
不是毒药
It's not poison.
太棒了
It's great.
谁说塞尔维亚人什么都做不出来? ！
Who says Serbs cannot make anything?!
给我来2公斤
Give me 2kg.
我得出去办点事，待会儿过来取
I have to run an errand, but I'll pick it up afterwards.
- 不用找了 -给拿着
- No, thank you. - Here, take it...
谢谢你
Thank you.
两公斤? 天哪！
Two kilos? Jesus!
你好，请出示身份证
Hello. Can I see some ID's, please?
谢谢，搜他的身
Thank you. Search him.
看看他... 过来
Look at him... Come over here.
你在看什么，妈的！
What're you looking at. Fuck!
- 下午好 - 好不好要看情况
- Good afternoon. - That depends.
哈吉 · 阿索夫先生
Mr. Hadgy Arsov,
我是你的律师，安特·帕维利奇
I'm your lawyer, Ante Pavelich, PhD.
为您服务
At your service.
- 你有烟吗? - 有，给你
- Do you have a cigarette? - Yes. Here you are.
给你
Here...
多么荣幸啊，博士为我辩护
What an honour. I'll be defended by a doctor.
你不是去年在斯科普里审判时的顾问吗？
Weren't you an adviser in Skopje trials last year?
是的，怎么了？
Yes. Why?
你的表现并不是很出色
Your performance wasn't exactly stellar.
那只是个模拟审判
You know it was a mock trial,
而且你的革命同志们都死定了
and that your IMRO mates were doomed.
你凭什么认为我现在还有机会？
So what makes you think I have a chance now?
你说得好像我们在赌博一样
You're talking as if we're at the gambling table.
我们在为胜利而战
But we are playing to win.
你说话像是个密码学家，而不是律师
And you're talking as if you're a cryptographer, not a lawyer.
那是什么意思？
What's that supposed to mean?
意思是我们和布科沃的朋友达成了协议
It means we made a deal with our friends from Bukovo,
与斯科普里不同的是
that, unlike in Skopje,
这一次，我们不会依赖塞尔维亚人称之为国家的
this time we won't rely on the corrupt legal system
这种可憎腐败法律制度
of this abomination that Serbs like to call the state.
我猜你喜欢陀思妥耶夫斯基
I see you like Dostoyevsky.
我给你带来了歌德的作品《浮士德》
I brought you Goethe. Faust.
你知道，那些斯拉夫语的废话
You know, all that Slavic nonsense
会让你对现实麻木不仁
can make you somewhat insensitive to reality.
甚至变软弱
Or even soft.
看一些真正的日耳曼哲学不会有什么害处，对吧？
A little true Germanic philosophy won't hurt, right?
我在一战朝他们开枪了吗？
I shot at them in the Great War?
也许是时候向他们学习了
Well, it might be time to learn something from them.
回见
See you... Soon.
谢谢你
Thank you.
塞尔维亚南部 弗兰涅 警察检查站
POLICE CHECKPOINT, VRANJE, SOUTHERN SERBIA,
南斯拉夫王国
KINGDOM OF SERBS, CROATS, AND SLOVENES
- 去哪儿? - 贝尔格莱德
- Where to? - Belgrade.
- 逃离比托尔? - 不，布科沃
- Escaping Bitol? - No, escaping Bukovo.
你们是马其顿人吗？
Are you Macedonians?
不，我们是印第安人
No, we're Indians.
- 你们有武器吗? - 没有
- Are you armed? - No.
我没看到武器
They're not, they're not.
走吧，开车
C'mon then, go... Open it.
验尸报告
Autopsy report.
受害者先被下药，然后被斩首
The victim was drugged, then beheaded.
- 看起来是同一个凶手 - 有可能
- Looks like a same killer. - Probably.
或者是犯罪世界的新潮流
Or it's some new fashion in the world of crime.
这个不流行，给你报告
This one's not into fashion. Here's the report.
- 谢谢 - 再见
- Thank you. - Goodbye.
博雅纳..
Boyana...
星期天你愿意和我一起出去吗？
Would you like to go out with me on Sunday?
我们可以散散步，找个地方吃晚饭
We can have a walk and go somewhere for dinner.
为什么？
Why?
我欠你一个道歉
I owe you an apology.
你说过你想带我参观这个小镇
You said you wanted to show me the town,
但是我不明白你为什么要和我约会
but I didn't understand it as your intention to go out with me.
你吓了我一跳...我想再要一次机会
You surprised me... And I'd like another opportunity.
博雅纳，我理解你
Boyana, I understand you.
我知道你在做一件高尚的事..
I know that you are doing something noble...
因为你是个与众不同的女人
because you are an exceptional woman.
我有时候会想..
I sometimes think...
斯大林帮了我们一个忙
that Stalin has done us a favour.
那个共产主义恶棍... 帮了什么忙？
That communist scoundrel... Why?
他把这些美丽的女人
He exiled all these beautiful women
正好流放到了我们怀里
right into our hands.
我不知道..
I don't know...
女人还不都是一样，对吧姑娘们！
Pussy is just a pussy for me. Isn't that right, girls?!
- 晚上好，对不起我迟到了，我...-哦，阿林皮耶，你迟到了..
- Good evening. Sorry I'm late, I... - Oh, Alimpiye, but you're late...
- 我有些事情要处理 - 运输方面的问题对吧？
- I had some previous engagements. - Problems with transport, right?
那是个误会
It was a misunderstanding.
- 我会赔偿一切损失 - 别担心，我对你有信心
- Any damage will be compensated. - Don't worry, I have faith in you.
加布里埃尔 · 马赫特先生
Mr. Gabriel Macht,
来自维也纳的朋友
our friend and associate from Vienna.
他会帮你安排和海姆达法姆公司的会议
He will help you with that arrangement with “Hymdalpharm”.
这是我的荣幸
It is an honour. Alimpiye Mirich.
海姆达法姆是一家知名公司，这很好
Hymdalpharm is a well-known company. That's great.
不是很出名，米里奇先生
Not well-known, Mr. Mirich.
高效、稳定、坚固
Efficient, stable and solid,
- 就像日耳曼人一样 - 你说得没错
- like Germanic people. - You're absolutely right.
强大的德国人民..
Powerful German people...
得了吧，阿林皮耶！
C'mon, Alimpiye!
谁在乎你怎么想? ！
Who gives a shit about what you think?!
- 伯爵，不必这么直言不讳 - 为什么？
- No need be so blunt, Count. - Why?
我想听听米里奇先生想说什么
I'd like to hear what Mr. Mirich wanted to say.
根据希腊传说，赫拉克勒斯去拿金苹果的时候
According to the Greek legend, Hercules visited the Germanic lands
曾到过日耳曼人的土地
when he went to get the Apples of the Hesperides.
从那以后
And ever since then,
德国人上战场时，用歌声赞扬他
Germans praised him in songs when they went to wars.
- 哇，你读过塔西佗的著作 - 是的
- Wow, you read Tacitus. - I did.
你要吃苹果吗? 和鸦片很配
Would you like some apples? They go well with opium.
太棒了，阿林皮耶，太棒了! 作为一个药剂师，你真是博学多才
Bravo, Alimpiye, bravo! You're well-read for a pharmacist.
好极了！
Excellent!
先生们，希望你们玩得开心
Gentlemen, I hope you're enjoying yourselves.
一如既往，我亲爱的朋友
As always, dear friend.
- 进来坐会儿 - 我还有事
- Join us, there's enough space. - I don't have time.
有事? 我倒是听说你跟那个什么和尚有点什么事
Problems? I hear you have problems with some monks.
他们让你很为难，至少我是这么听说的
Who are giving you a hard time. Or so I heard.
先生们的香槟！
Champagne for the gentlemen!
不用了，谢谢，我想要..
No, thank you. I'd like...
你们有俄罗斯冰镇格瓦斯吗？
Do you have cold Russian Kvas?
这里没有俄国货，只有塞尔维亚产品
We don't have Russian, only Serbian.
太好了! 给我一杯塞尔维亚咖啡，谢谢
Excellent! Give me a Serbian one, thank you.
准备好了吗，亲爱的？
Ready to go, my love?
请不要忘记请将军在资助玛雅的银行
Please don't forget to ask the general to help Maya with the bank.
不知道他会不会同意
Not sure he'll agree.
- 他一定还记得阿森纳 - 但你可能会改变他的想法
- He remembers Arseniye. - But you may change his mind.
- 好吧，我试试 - 你太棒了
- Okay, I'll try. - You're wonderful.
爱你，旅途愉快
Love you. Have a nice trip.
- 你忘了带伞! - 不用啦！
- You forgot your umbrella! - I don't need it!
别忘了玛雅！
Don't forget about Maya!
克里斯塔·阿瓦库莫维奇？
Krista Avakumovich?
你是谁？
Who are you?
你朋友派我来的
Your friend sent me.
这个给你
I'm supposed to give you this.
祝你今天过得愉快
Have a nice day.
- 你以前手法更好 - 我每晚都梦到你
- You used to do this better. - I dreamt of you every night.
- 你这个骗子! - 好吧，不是每晚
- You liar! - Okay, not every night.
死鬼，我以为你死了，留下我一个人
Fuck off, I thought you died and left me alone.
你什么时候一个人过？
When have you ever been alone?
你的丈夫呢? 你的屁股..
Where's that husband of yours? Your ass...
你那个资产阶级老公会这样干你吗？
Does that bourgeois hubby fuck you like this?
他跟你做吗，婊子？
Is he doing you, whore?
淦! 没事的
Oh, fuck! It's okay.
没什么，没事
It's nothing. It's fine.
哇，他们处决你的时候你还想保持体型吗？
Wow, you want to be in shape when they execute you?
是的
Yep.
我带来了马其顿的烤猪肉
A roasted pig from Macedonia.
抚慰你的怀旧之情
To soothe your nostalgia.
我以为你不会再来了
I thought you were finished with me.
你得到了你想要的
You got what you wanted.
想到你可能不久于人世，我也不好过
It wouldn't be a consolation to see you six feet under.
塔纳西耶维奇上尉身上还有骑士精神吗
Is there still some chivalry in Captain Tanasiyevich,
或许只是良心不安？
or just a guilty conscience?
你这个月有个听证会
You have a hearing this month.
我询问了法官的情况，然后开始谈判
I asked about the judge. I started to negotiate.
塞尔维亚的大人物会争先恐后地帮助马其顿的恐怖分子，不是吗？
And Serb big shots will scramble to help Macedonian terrorist, right?
不，是你那个花哨的律师
No, that's for your fancy faggot of a lawyer,
他讨厌塞尔维亚人，因为他们不让他跪舔德国人
who hates Serbs because they won't let him kiss German asses.
他的工作是帮忙
His job is to help.
你的工作就是埋葬我
And your people's job is to bury me.
真的吗？
Oh, really?
那他为什么不要求更改起诉书？
Why didn't he ask for change of indictment?
因此你不会因叛国罪受审
So you're not tried for treason,
而是一些不会挨子弹的罪名
but for something you won't get shot for.
给我一支烟
Give me a cig.
你们 IMRO 的人都是混蛋
You IMRO people are assholes,
但帕维里奇有些过分了
but that Pavelich is a bit too much.
即使对你来说
Even for you.
多亏了你们的人，我们现在只能靠墙等死了
We're up against a wall thanks to your people.
在这种情况下
And in a situation like that,
已经没有选择盟友的余地了
you don't really get to choose your allies.
所以你必须和魔鬼做个约定？
So you have to make a pact... with the Devil himself?
该死..
Dame...
你的伙伴们可能已经准备好了
Your pals may indeed be ready for that,
但是你，我的朋友..
but you, my friend...
你不是那种人，我了解你
You're not like that. I know you.
塔尼，我告诉过你，不要为了一个混蛋和你的人作对
Tane, I told you, don't mess with your people over an asshole.
管好你自己的事
And mind your own business.
我原谅你，兄弟
I forgive you, brother.
不好意思
Excuse me...
这是亚塔汉贫民窟吗？
Is this Yatagan slum?
不，我的朋友，这里是贝尔格莱德
No, my friend. It's Belgrade.
- 我就是这个意思，贝尔格莱德 - 对，亚塔甘贫民窟
- That's what I meant, Belgrade. - Yep, Yatagan slum.
好吧，到底是亚塔汉贫民窟还是贝尔格莱德？
Okay, Yatagan slum or Belgrade?
都是，随你喜欢
It's both. However you like it.
我也说不清楚
The jury is out.
别废话了，回答我的问题
C'mon, cut the crap and answer the question.
听着，马其顿人，这个在我们这不好使
Look, Macedonian, we don't do things that way around here.
在哪里? 贝尔格莱德还是贫民窟？
Around where? In Belgrade or in the slum?
贝尔格莱德，贫民窟也是一样
In Belgrade. And in the slum.
我要找一个男人，特纳瓦茨
I need a man. They call him Trnavatz.
你是第一个叫他男人的人
You're the first person to ever call him a man.
看到那边的酒馆了吗，“尼什客栈”？
See that tavern over there, "Niish Inn"?
但是要小心
But be careful.
里面有许多恶棍
There are many scoundrels inside.
比我身后那些恶棍还恶棍? 我可不这么认为
Worse than those rats behind me? I don't think so.
米利萨夫，你这个白痴！
Milisav, you stupid idiot!
你为什么放他走，你这个笨蛋？
Why did you let him go, you stupid git?
那我该怎么办? 让他死在这？
What was I supposed to do? Let him die?
怎么会死? 他一点事都没有
From what? There was nothing wrong with him.
但是医生说..
But the doctor said...
去他妈的医生，你应该马上给我打电话
Fuck the doctor. You should've called me right away.
你说过你会来的
You said you'd come.
你又喝醉了，不是我的错
It's not my fault you got drunk again.
听我说，如果他出了什么事
Listen to me, if anything happens to him,
我就废了你！
you are fucked!
快滚！
Now, get lost!
督察先生请给我点吃的
Inspector, sir, give me some food.
走开！
Move away!
特纳瓦茨在哪儿？
Where's Trnavatz?
明知故问
Beating a dead horse with Macedonians.
不要打碎我的家具
Don't smash my furniture.
嘿，兄弟... 你去哪儿了
Hey, bro... Where've you been.
出去
Get out.
滚！
Get out!
这些马其顿人只是路过？
These Macedonians just dropped by?
坐
Sit.
我问你，你为什么要这样？
Let me ask you something. Why are you acting like this?
如果你问他，他给你让位置的
He'd have given you a chair if you asked him.
而你却把他赶出去了，他被你吓得直接逃走
You chased him out. He's afraid of you and he ran away.
所以我问你，你为什么要这么做？
So I'm asking you, why are you acting like this?
- 关他妈你什么事? - 当然关我的事
- What the fuck do you care? - I do care.
我非常在乎
I care very much.
你无法想象我有多在乎
You can't even imagine how much I care.
我不想和白痴一起工作
I don't want to work with idiots.
一粒老鼠屎，坏了一锅粥
One idiot can spoil a hundred smart people.
他在说什么？
What is he talking about?
冷静，冷静... 大家都冷静点
Easy, easy... Let's calm down, everyone.
这是来自布科沃的卡罗大师
It's Master Kyro... from Bukovo.
哦，原来是卡罗大师..
Oh, Master Kyro...
你这个老混蛋... 我还纳闷呢
You old fucker... And here I am, wondering
这么小的卡车怎么能装这么多马其顿人？
how could such a small truck pack so many Macedonians?
那么... 卡罗大师，你想喝点什么？
So... Master Kyro, what would you like to drink?
我要你带我去见和尚
I want you to take me to the Monk.
我要见他
I want to see him.
算了吧，卡罗，是俄国人杀了塔蒂奇
Let it go, Kyro. The Russians killed Tatich.
我们无能为力
There was nothing we could do. Nothing.
塔蒂奇是个人渣，真正的人渣
Tatich was a scum. A real scum.
他做事不过脑子
He strikes without thinking.
我要你带我去见和尚
I want you to take me to Monk.
有些事我想问他
There's something I want to ask him.
这是你第二次说那个名字了
This is the second time you said that name.
那又怎样？
So?
在这里你不能说那个名字
You don't say that name around here.
我不会再提醒你了
I don't want it mentioned. Not by you,
也不会再提醒你的这群猴子
and not by any of your monkeys.
明白吗？
Understood?
听我说..
Listen to me...
我也不想提这个名字，但我要见那个人！
I don't want to mention the name, I want to see the man!
裁缝店，下午好
Tailor's shop. Good afternoon.
我不是告诉过你我会联系你? 你不应该打给我，什么事？
Didn't I tell you I'd call you. You shouldn't call me. What is it?
来自布科沃的马其顿人
The Macedonians from Bukovo.
他们在亚塔汉的贫民窟，有五六个人
They're in Yatagan slum. Five or six of them.
淦！
Fuck!
- 他们带货来了吗? - 没有，卡罗大师带头来的
- Did they bring any merchandise? - No. Master Kyro is with them.
他说在他见到老板之前不会有任何问题
Says there won't be any before he talks to the boss.
- 好的，带上他，不要带其他人 - 明白
- Okay. Bring him. Alone. - Got it.
那个摄影师是怎么回事？
What happened with that photographer...
不是我做的
It wasn't me.
那底片呢？
And the negatives?
- 那个社交名媛还留着呢 - 好吧，控制住她
- That socialite still has them. - Okay, squeeze her.
- 但是不要太夸张了 - 好的
- But don't overdo it. - Okay.
- 下午好，将军 - 下午好
- Good afternoon, general. - Good afternoon.
- 你身体怎么样? - 非常好，非常好..
- How's your health? - Excellent, excellent...
只要我不是你的病人就好
As long as I'm not your patient.
我不是这个意思，上帝保佑！
That's not what I meant. God forbid!
- 请坐 - 谢谢
- Have a seat. - Thank you.
情况是这样的，你要去一趟托波尼卡
This is the situation: You have to go to Toponica,
检查一下那个可怜的混蛋
examine that miserable bastard,
并在他的病例上写清楚：
and to write down in his medical record
- 他不适合旅行 - 他不适合
- that he's unfit to travel. - Well, he's not.
乔尔杰·卡拉乔尔杰维奇王子病得很重
Prince Djordje Karadjordjevich is a very sick man.
是的
Yes.
而且他至少要病上两三年
And he should stay sick for at least two or three years.
简直是疯了
That means crazy as a coconut.
我们收到一封意大利国王的信
We got a letter from the Italian king...
他主动提出带王子去治疗
He offered to take him in for a treatment.
他们认为我疯了
They think I'm crazy.
难道我不知道这一切都是叶连娜干的吗？
Like I don't know that all this is Yelena's doing?
你不能因为一个姑妈担心她侄子的健康而责怪她
You can't blame an aunt for worrying about her nephew's health.
但我可以... 我们的国王有麻烦了
Oh, but I can... Our King is in trouble.
法国人叛变了
The French are turning their backs.
意大利人得到乔尔杰王子
If Italians get Djordje, it's just the matter of time
那么他夺回王位只是时间问题，你明白吗？
before he comes back to reclaim the throne, do you understand?
别担心
Don't worry.
我的专家意见是乔尔杰·卡拉乔尔杰维奇王子
It is my expert opinion that prince Djordje Karadjordjevich
无法适应改变环境
is not ready to change environment.
太好了! 太棒了！
Great! Excellent!
现在，只要贴上邮票，我就可以答复意大利人了
Now, just stamp it, so I can stick it up to Italians.
对不起，正如你们专家所言，我有压力
I'm sorry, I'm under pressure, as you experts would say.
我们不都是一样吗? 还有一件事..
Aren't we all? One more thing...
有人让我问你点事
I've been asked to ask you something.
是关于玛雅 · 达维多维奇的抵押银行,
It's about the mortgage bank of Maya Davidovich,
已故达维多维奇的女儿
daughter of late Arseniye Davidovich.
我认识他
I knew him personally.
阿塞尼耶是一个自以为是、卑鄙无耻的小偷
Arseniye was a smug, a scruge, and a thief.
- 他女儿也好不到哪儿去 - 将军先生
- And his daughter is no better. - Mr. General,
封锁这样一个稳定而富有的银行有什么好处？
what's the use of having such a stable and rich bank blocked?
我知道，但我不能解决所有问题
I know, but I can't solve everything.
但即使我可以，我宁愿帮助拉亚奇基和他的团伙
But even if I could, I'd rather help Rayachky and his gang.
明白吗？
Understand?
他在等你
He's waiting.
- 我不想看到他! - 你不用看，听我说
- I cannot look at him! - You don't have to. Just listen.
也许你能想出合作的方法
Maybe you'll work it out. Find the way to cooperate.
就像他和我爸爸合作一样，绝不可能！
Just as he cooperated with my dad. No way!
我只是不知道我父亲是疯了还是傻了
I just don't know if my father was insane or stupid,
更重要的是，这是遗传的吗？
And more importantly, is it hereditary?
亲爱的，你从你父母那里继承了最好的东西
My dear, you inherited the best from both of your parents
金钱
Money.
听听他想说什么，就当是为了我
Listen to him. Do it for me.
让他进来吧
Let him in, Taki.
请进
Please come in.
- 你好，先生 - 你是说... 伯爵？
- Hello, sir. - You mean... count?
你的伯爵头衔只在奥匈帝国有效
Your title is valid only in Austro-Hungarian Empire.
那个国家已经不复存在了，还有你们的皇室
That country has ceased to exist. And with it, your royalty.
你父亲可不是这么想的
Your father didn't think like that.
我父亲眼瞎了，竟然和你合作
My father was mindless enough to work with you.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
我的股东和我都在想..
My shareholders and I were wondering...
鉴于最近发生的事情，你改变主意了吗？
if you had changed your mind in light of the recent events?
我不知道你指的是什么事件
I don't know what events you're referring to,
但我没有改变主意
but no, I haven't changed my mind.
但我相信你会的
But you will, I'm sure,
当你嫁给沃因·朱基奇，成为一个受人尊敬的女人之后
when you marry Voyin Djukich, and become a respectable woman.
你就没有时间去管理银行了
You won't have time for the bank.
得到一笔可观的补偿金不是更明智吗？
Wouldn't it be wiser to get a handsome payout?
你怎么知道我会结婚？
Where did you get the idea that I'm getting married?
这是全镇的话题，你的情人现在自由了
It's the talk of the town. And your lover is free now.
你愿意娶你的情人吗，拉亚奇基先生？
And do you marry your lovers, Mr. Rayachki?
- 但愿不会这样 - 听着，我们可以做个交易
- God forbid. - Listen, we may have a deal,
如果你告诉我你在维也纳的神秘搭档是谁
if you disclose your silent partner from Vienna?
你太天真了，小姐，你负担不起你父亲的股份
You're naive, Miss. You can't afford you father's shares.
但我有权知道谁是第三个合伙人！
But I do have the right to know who's the third co-owner!
如果你父亲想让你知道，他会告诉你的
Your father would've told you if he wanted to.
在我看来，你可以顽固到底
As far as I'm concerned, you can remain stubborn to the end.
你的法庭禁令毫无意义
Your court injunction means nothing.
我们最终会推翻它
We'll overturn it eventually.
没有时间做交易了
And there'll be no time for making deals.
祝你今天过得愉快
Have a nice day.
帕帕哈吉，这越来越无聊了
Papahagi, this is getting tedious.
你可以想象我的感受
You can imagine how it is for me.
我和老板谈过了，他向我保证你不会打扰她
I talked to the boss and he gave me his word you won't bother her.
一切都会好起来的，只要一点点耐心
It'll all end well, just a little patience.
好吧，但是我的耐心真的只剩一点点了
Okay, but... Really just a little.
维达，请把你的手举起来，朱尔贾，再低一点..
Vida keep your hand up, please, Djurdja little lower...
- 我做不到，你疯了吗? - 你可以的
- I can't do this. Are you crazy? - Yes, you can.
艾弗拉姆，有人来了
Avram, we have company.
- 你好，督察 - 哇，督察... 你好
- Hello, inspector. - Wow, inspector... Hello.
你好
Hello.
- 一个害羞的督查先生 - 好了，继续摆姿势
- A shy inspector. - Okay, okay, back in the pose.
告诉我，你没有参加维奥莱塔的葬礼？
Tell me, you didn't go to Violet's funeral?
我在警察局告诉过你，我们关系没那么好
I told you in the police station we were not that close.
你一定是为内文 · 萨里奇的事来这里的吧？
Are you must be here because of what happened to Neven Sarich?
是的，节哀顺变
Yes. My condolences.
谢谢
Thanks.
我们还没缓过神来，他是我们的朋友
We're still in shock. He was our friend.
一位伟大的摄影师，所有这些照片都是他拍的
A great photographer. All these pictures are his.
基于达维多维奇女士概念的非凡艺术作品
Extraordinary works of art based on Ms. Davidovich's concept.
的确如此
Indeed they are.
但是你不觉得他们有点太“自由”了吗？
But don't you think they're a bit too "free"?
我们来给你自由一下不好吗？
Shall we set you free a little bit?
如果你是一个艺术爱好者，请拿一些我们的产品目录
If you're an art lover, feel free to take some of our catalogues.
我的作品才刚刚开始
My works are at the beginning.
告诉我，你最后一次见到内文是什么时候？
Tell me, when was the last time you saw Neven?
在警察局，你审问我们的时候
At the police station, when you questioned us.
之后他就被杀了
He was killed after that
为什么这么问？
Why do you ask?
探长... 你是在怀疑我吗？
Inspector... Are you questioning me?
- 探长! - 啊？
- Inspector! - Yes...
不不
No, no.
请继续，我道歉，祝你今天愉快
Carry on, please. I apologise. Enjoy your day.
继续
Let's go.
塔妮，我不知道，我只和安静的病人一起工作
Tane, I don't know that, I only work with quiet patients.
我不能碰温暖的血液，我不知道
I can't touch the warm blood. I don't know that.
你会知道的
You'll know.
米利萨夫，过来
Milisav! Come over here.
听他说: “我不能! 我不知道... ...”
Listen to him: "I can't! I don't know..."
我的好医生，男人就要做男人该做的事
My good doctor, a man's got to do what a man's got to do.
我就是这样在1914年过了萨瓦河，来到这里的
That's how I ended up here, in 1914, when I crossed the Sava river.
该死的奥地利人让我参军，让我朝自己的亲人开枪
Bloody Austrians had me drafted, made me shoot at my own kin.
但是我说，不行! 只要等到夜幕降临
But I said, no way! Just wait till the night falls.
夜幕降临，军官们都睡着了
And when the night fell, and the officers were asleep,
我向河边游去，游到了对岸
I made my way to the river and swam across to the other side.
游过去需要一些勇气..
It took some guts to swim across...
我不会游泳，我很害怕，但是我不得不跳下河
I couldn't swim and I was afraid. But I had to, and I jumped.
你就是那时候发现那个桶的吗？
Was that when you found that barrel?
- 是的 - 这就是为什么
- Yes. - And is that why
你的酒馆叫”萨瓦的桶”？
your tavern is called "The barrel of Sava"?
看在上帝的份上，你真的很无聊
For Christ's sakes, you really are boring.
这个故事你讲了一百多遍了! 妈的！
You told that story a hundred times! Fuck!
- 那个人叫什么名字? - 我在哪儿能找到他？
- What's the name of that man? - Where can I find him?
米利萨夫会解释一切的，去吧！
Milisav will explain everything. Go!
- 你好 - 你是谁？
- Hello. - Who are you?
别害怕，没事的
Don't be afraid. It's all right.
我不是来伤害你的
I didn't come here to hurt you.
这里很好，很宽敞，我喜欢
It's nice here, very spacious. I like it.
这些画都是你自己画的吗？
You painted all this by yourself?
- 是你杀了内文吗? - 这已经不重要了
- Did you kill Neven? - That's really not important now.
你知道你要给我什么
You know what you have to give me,
就是为再也见不到我而付出的小小代价，对吧？
and that's a small price to pay for never seeing me again? Right?
把帽子给我
Give me the hat.
滚出去！
Get lost!
如果我再见到你，你会后悔的
If I ever see you again, you'll be sorry.
好吧
Okay.
还有一个承诺: 如果我们再见面
And here's a promise too: If we do meet again,
你不会注意到我的
you will not see me.
你是做什么的? 学生吗？
What are you? A student?
我是个画家
I'm a painter.
画家加共产主义者等于一个双重白痴
A painter and a communist, a double idiot.
那你呢，理发师，你是学生吗？
And you, barber, are you also a student?
我是一个工人，无产主义者
I'm a worker, a proletarian.
恭喜你，拉吉丁！
Congratulations, Rakitin!
你在塞尔维亚拍了一部芭蕾舞剧！
You made a ballet in Serbia!
将军..
General...
如果你不介意的话，我们现在要去完成我们的工作了
if you don't mind, we would now leave to finish our business.
好的，完成了告诉我
Alright. Let me know when it's done.
同志们，准备好了吗？
Comrades, is everything ready?
我们的两个人正在等待命令
Two of our guys are on it, awaiting orders.
去吧，艺术家!  理发师，你等一下
Move it, artist! Barber, you wait.
我们不想引起怀疑
We don't want to look suspicious.
时刻保持学习，革命不喜欢无知的人
Learn, the Revolution doesn't like the ignorants.
督察，你在这儿啊
Inspector, there you are.
我到处找你
I've been looking all over for you.
给你，照片洗好了
Here, it's finished.
如果有人问起的话，这不是我洗的
If anybody asks, I didn't develop this,
我什么也没看到，也没听到
I didn't see or hear anything.
沃伦格尔将军，好久不见
General Vrangel, long time no see.
我希望你知道，你一直是值得尊敬的客人
I hope you know that you are always a very dear guest?
是的，这就是问题所在
Yes. That's the problem.
无论走到哪里，我都是客人
I'm a guest wherever I go.
好吧，将军..
Well, general...
在上帝的帮助下，布尔什维克将自我毁灭
With God's help, Bolsheviks will destroy themselves.
真的吗？
Themselves?
我来介绍一下，这位是阿利姆皮耶 · 米里奇先生,
Let me introduce you. This is Mr. Alimpiye Mirich,
我们国家最成功的人之一
one of the most successful people in our country.
- 我的荣幸 - 我也是
- My pleasure. - Mine too.
这位是加布里埃尔 · 马赫特先生,
And this is Mr. Gabriel Macht,
我们尊敬的维也纳朋友
our respected friend from Vienna.
米里奇先生是个重要的赞助人，没有他的帮助..
Mr. Mirich is an important patron. Without his help...
请不要说了
Please don't.
这只是一个小小的感谢
It's just a small token of appreciation
为了你伟大的艺术和传统
for your great art and tradition.
你对芭蕾舞感兴趣吗？
Are you interested in ballet?
印象深刻
I am impressed
不朽的柴可夫斯基是如何将斯拉夫人的灵魂编织进德国神话的
how the immortal Tchaikovsky weaved the Slavic soul into the German myth.
爱，激情，背叛，最后是宽恕
Love, passion, betrayal and finally forgiveness.
所以俄罗斯人，有很多灵魂
So Russian, with a lot of soul.
你对灵魂感兴趣吗？
Are you interested in the soul?
- 灵魂最让我兴奋了 - 我也是
- It excites me most. - Me too.
好极了！
Excellent!
回你们的房间去! 快！
Go to your rooms! Quickly!
看看那些护士
Check out the nurses.
- 可不是吗 - 要我给你介绍一个吗
- Yes. - Shall I introduce you to one.
认真点，我们在站岗
Get serious, we're on guard duty.
他哪儿也去不了，快死了
He's not going anywhere. He's about to kick the bucket.
我饿死了，我们去吃点东西吧
I'm starving. Let's go grab a bite.
好吧，我们先吃点东西，然后再看看这些小妞
Okay, let's eat first, and then we can check out these chicks.
- 好吧 - 来吧，斯维塔..
- Fine. - C'mon, Sveta...
看起来不错
This looks fine.
伤口很干净
The wound is clean.
我不会失去我的腿吧？
I'm not going to lose my leg?
告诉你这件事的人应该被取消学位
Whoever told you that should lose their degree.
塔尼知道了肯定会发疯
Tane will be mad when he hears about this.
医生！
Doctor!
我们走！
Let's go!